<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writings on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writings on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 20:52:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/writings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Google&#39;s Stance on Advertising in 1998; The case for Kagi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/google-advertising-and-kagi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 20:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/google-advertising-and-kagi/</guid>
      <description>It is interesting to read the original technical paper from Google, The Anatomy of a Large-Scale Hypertextual Web Search Engine, where Larry Page and Sergey Brin explicitly call out advertising reduces the quality of a search engine. Some of the best lines are:&#xA;The goals of the advertising business model do not always correspond to providing quality search to users.&#xA;We expect that advertising funded search engines will be inherently biased towards the advertisers and away from the needs of the consumers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jacob on the Shortness of Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/jacob-on-the-shortness-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 21:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/jacob-on-the-shortness-of-life/</guid>
      <description>Seneca comes out guns ablazin&amp;rsquo; right in the first few pages of On the Shortness of Life:&#xA;It is not that we have a short time to live, but that we waste a lot of it. Life is long enough, and a sufficiently generous amount of time has been given to us for the highest achievements if it were all well invested.&#xA;People are frugal in guarding their personal property; but as soon as it comes to squandering time they are most wasteful of the one thing in which it is right to be stingy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding History and Trade-offs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/understanding-history-and-trade-offs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 16:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/understanding-history-and-trade-offs/</guid>
      <description>There Are No Zero-cost Abstractions I recently watched Chandler Carruth&amp;rsquo;s excellent talk entitled “There Are No Zero-cost Abstractions”. In it, he outlines that there are no abstractions in programming that are truly zero cost. He says there are three categories in which this cost can end up:&#xA;Compile time cost Run time cost Human cost Chandler&amp;rsquo;s premise is that the cost doesn&amp;rsquo;t go to zero, but rather, it just gets shuffled around.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guiding Principles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/guiding-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 16:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/guiding-principles/</guid>
      <description>I recently turned down a research role I was super excited to join. It paid well, it was part-time so I could continue with my current job, and I would have grown a lot as an engineer. It sounds perfect on paper, so why did I turn it down? As I meditated on whether accepting it would be the right thing to do, I realized I would be doing it for the wrong reasons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Playing with Generics in Go: Making Event Payloads More Extensible</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/playing-with-generics-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 16:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/playing-with-generics-in-go/</guid>
      <description>With the advent of generics in Go 1.18, I wanted to spend some time getting familiar with them. At a previous job, I wrote a microservice in Go that handled incoming events from a message queue and looked at their type to determine what to do with them. When writing that service, I always felt like generics would be a good fit to ease some of the pains I had when implementing all the possible payload types.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upload Multiple Files with Go</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/upload-multiple-files-with-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 11:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/upload-multiple-files-with-go/</guid>
      <description>I was recently working on a feature that would allow a client to upload multiple files to a server. There was already a method to upload one file with a POST of type multipart/form-data, but it was limiting to upload one file at a time. Because of this, I started looking at what the best method would be to handle uploading multiple files in bulk. I tried a few different approaches until I stumbled upon the fact that multipart/form-data already supports uploading multiple files in one request.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimize for the Common Case</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/optimize-for-the-common-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 06:12:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/optimize-for-the-common-case/</guid>
      <description>I have this long-running joke/belief with a friend that many concepts within Computer Science actually translate to everyday life really well. One such example is Optimizing for the Common Case. I couldn’t find a good link that gives a complete overview of this concept, but from a Compiler Optimization Wikipedia page, it says the following:&#xA;The common case may have unique properties that allow a fast path at the expense of a slow path.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enjoy the Process</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/enjoy-the-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 08:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/enjoy-the-process/</guid>
      <description>I was meditating today with a 10 minute breathing exercise. The whole way through, all I could think about was wanting to check how much longer I had left. After struggling with that for a while, I had an epiphany - I do this in all areas of my life. I am constantly rearranging my class schedule to see if I can graduate faster, planning my next career goals, and making long lists of projects I want to complete to be better at computer graphics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Euler’s Method and Approximating the Future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/eulers-method-and-approximating-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 14:40:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/eulers-method-and-approximating-the-future/</guid>
      <description>I think that the Euler&amp;rsquo;s Method can give us insight into how we can get closer to who we want to be and live more fulfilling lives. Even though the concepts described are simple, there are still pitfalls I run into when I try to live by them. Because of this, I also want to explore a little why I think I often fail at implementing these ideas into my own life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greatness &amp; Dijkstra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/greatness--dijkstra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 22:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/greatness--dijkstra/</guid>
      <description>Lid est laborum et dolorum fuga. Et harum quidem rerum facilis est et expeditasi distinctio. Nam libero tempore, cum soluta nobis est eligendi optio cumque nihilse impedit quo minus id quod amets untra dolor amet sad. Sed ut perspser iciatis unde omnis iste natus error sit voluptatem accusantium doloremque laste. Dolores sadips ipsums sits.&#xA;Heading 1 Lid est laborum et dolorum fuga. Et harum quidem rerum facilis est et expeditasi distinctio.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Maximas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writings/local-maximas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 22:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writings/local-maximas/</guid>
      <description>Lid est laborum et dolorum fuga. Et harum quidem rerum facilis est et expeditasi distinctio. Nam libero tempore, cum soluta nobis est eligendi optio cumque nihilse impedit quo minus id quod amets untra dolor amet sad. Sed ut perspser iciatis unde omnis iste natus error sit voluptatem accusantium doloremque laste. Dolores sadips ipsums sits.&#xA;Heading 1 Lid est laborum et dolorum fuga. Et harum quidem rerum facilis est et expeditasi distinctio.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
